Anatoliy Yastreb

Software Engineer

Bilker Allee 196, Düsseldorf, Germany 40215 +49 177 7817203

> anatoliy.yastreb@gmail.com https://ayastreb.me

I'm a web software engineer with 5 years experience in eCommerce and overall 10 years of experience in web development. I have led teams of 3 to 4 developers and have experience setting up team workflow according to industry's best practices.

I'm passionate about complete process of product development - from collecting requirements to deployment and impact analysis. I enjoy working with smart people, crafting software which brings value to customers, and continuously improving my skills.

In my free time I contribute to open source projects and learn new technologies, like Ruby, AngularJS, ReactJS and others.

Experience

Senior Software Developer at Luxury Fashion Trade GmbH (fashionette.de)

Düsseldorf, Germany, 2013 - 2016

Technologies: Magento, PHP, Laravel, Solr, Varnish, Microservices

Led development team of 3-4 in various projects, including new features implementation, payment methods integration and online shop localization in 16 new countries for Germany's biggest online designer handbags retailer.

Senior Software Engineer at Magento, X.commerce, Inc. (an eBay company)

Dnipropetrovsk, Ukraine, 2011 – 2013

Technologies: PHP, SOAP WSI, REST, Redis, MongoDB, Gearman

Worked on Magento Core API, performed R&D on Magento 2 API platform. Participated in Magento Connect and Magento GO (SaaS) projects development.

Web Developer as Independent Contractor

Dnipropetrovsk, Ukraine, 2007 – 2010

Technologies: PHP, JavaScript, AWS, Solr

Implemented various projects, such as <u>DiccionarioLibre.com</u>, <u>ProfileStar.com</u>, <u>MyCubi.com</u>

Junior PHP Developer at eTek Systems

Dnipropetrovsk, Ukraine, 2006 - 2007

Technologies: PHP, XML, Atom

Worked on international customer's web projects and in-house tools.

Projects

Jekyll

Team Captain, 2016 – Present

As @jekyll/build team captain I help triaging incoming issues, review pull requests and occasionally contribute to bug fixes, refactoring and feature development.

Jekyll Maps

Maintainer, 2016 - Present

Jekyll Maps is a plugin that allows users to easily create different maps on Jekyll site pages.

Bandwidth Hero

Maintainer, 2016 - Present

Experimental Chrome extension which compresses images on the page via proxy server.

Proxy server is implemented with Node.js and uses Amazon S3 for file storage.

Meal-Planner.org

Founder & Primary Developer, 2015 - Present

Recipe recommendation and nutrition balancing service.

A health & fitness progressive web app built with AngularJS, Sinatra & ElasticSearch.

Education

Coursera

Data Structures and Algorithms, 2016

Udacity

Tech Entrepreneur Nanodegree, 2015 – 2016

National Mining University, Dnepropetrovsk, Ukraine

Bachelor, Management, Economics, 2004 – 2008

Skills

Languages

PHP, Ruby, JavaScript

Frameworks

Zend, Laravel, Sinatra, AngularJS

WebServices

SOAP, REST, JSON API, oAuth

Databases & Search

MySQL, Redis, ElasticSearch, Solr

Testing

PHPUnit, Rspec, Cucumber, Selenium, Jasmine

Continuous Integration

Bamboo, Capistrano, TravisCI